Muhammad Ahmad Khan

Software Engineer | Tech Evangelist

Summary

I'm a software engineer developing (and occasionally designing) exceptional digital experiences. I've had the privilege of working with multiple startups over the time building products having high user experience and performance. Being a tech evangelist, I've been a part of different tech communities like GDG, GDSC, Women Techmakers as a community manager and member.

Experience

• Jaldi Dubai, UAE (Remote)

Software Engineer

Mar 2022 - Present

Jaldi removes the pain of cold calling so your team can focus on what's really important -> Calling More and Closing More. Jaldi allows managers to reduce cold calling admin work by 80%!

- Deliver high-quality, robust production code for Jaldi's web & mobile apps in Flutter & Python
- Work alongside co-founders & other team members to research, and develop technical solutions to fulfill business requirements
- Collaborate with designers, & other engineers to transform creative concepts into production realities for clients & stakeholders
- Provide leadership within engineering department through close collaboration, and knowledge shares

• Google for Developers

Pakistan (Remote)

Jul 2021 - Present

 $GDG\ Organizer\ @GDG\ Live\ Pakistan$

Google Developer Groups (GDGs) are local community chapters for people interested in Google developer technologies

- Connecting digital Pakistan through online/onsite community events & networking sessions
- Building a community of 18,000+ folks collectively on multiple platforms
- Onboarding speakers & partners by leading community relations and partnerships for the chapter
- Implementing marketing strategies to increase brand recognition and social media engagements

• Flutter Lahore

Lahore, Pakistan

Community Organizer

Feb 2022 - Present

Flutter Lahore is a local community meetup group with a focus on helping developers in Flutter, Firebase, and Google Cloud

- Leading the chapter and organizing different events and workshops
- Building a local community ecosystem for Flutter developers in Lahore & surroundings

Cross Code Software Developer Lahore, Pakistan

Jul 2021 - Jun 2022

- Developed, maintained, & shipped production code for client & in-house mobile apps using Flutter, Firebase, & REST APIs
- Collaborated & co-authored an open-source package, Easy Ads, and published it on pub.dev

Hostinn

Pakistan

Marketing Lead

Jun 2018 - Mar 2020

Hostinn facilitates its users through its mobile app & website to search or book hostel rooms in Lahore, Islamabad & Rawalpindi

- Implemented & optimized digital marketing campaigns that led to a significant increase in user base
- Executed a multi-channel campaign, which led to a notable increase in brand recognition & social media engagement

Education

• University of the Punjab

Lahore, Pakistan

Bachelor of Computer Science

Final-year project: Maveshi (Built a mobile app to digitize local cattle farms)

Relevant coursework: Cloud Computing, Artificial Intelligence, Computer Vision, Mobile Computing, Enterprise Application Development, Analysis of Algorithms, OOP, DSA, Calculus I-II, Linear Algebra, etc.

Skillset

- Languages & frameworks: Flutter/Dart, iOS, Android, Firebase, Python, Flask, .NET, C/C++/C#
- **DevOps:** Git, GitHub, CI/CD, Basics of Cloud (GCP, AWS), Playstore/Appstore
- Soft skills: Creative, Organization, Leadership, Fast learner, Growth mindset, Team player

Email: rmahmadkhan@icloud.com Website: mahmadkhan.com